So what does conducting analysis look like?
This is where you're actually doing the work.
You've defined the problem, you've structured it,
you have your issues prioritised, and you're looking at
both the qualitative and quantitative sources of input.
The issue we often see here is
missing the forest for the trees.
You get so worried about the analysis that you don't step back
and think about how this leads to the “so what” of the answer,
or you get too concerned about the precision of the numbers
and not concerned enough with —
is this accurately leading us
to the solution to the problem?
One tip we often use is to force ourselves, as we go through
the analysis, to step back and sanity-check the results.
The trade-off there is often precision versus accuracy.
Say you can get to an answer
with three decimal places of precision.
But the question is: are you accurate, directionally?
Are you actually helping to address
the question you're trying to solve?
Also: do you know enough now to stop the analysis,
based on the work plan?
Or do you need to go further, if you hit a surprise,
and really test the hypotheses?
As you conduct the analysis, pause on a frequent basis.
It could be once a week, it could be once a month.
Think about how this has changed our view of what we know —
and what we need to know.
And are there ways we can change our plan
moving forward, to get to a better solution?